本作品由Norm HALFCD Team倾情奉献\N感谢原作提供资源.仅供学习交流.严禁用于商业行为\N请自觉于下载后24小时内删除!如果喜欢本片,请购买正版!
更多精彩 尽在www.NormTeam.com
压制:鬼谷子  字幕:鬼谷子\NCompression:GV-Sir  Subtitles:GV-Sir
飞天大盗 第2季第6集
S02E06 Eye of the Beholder
- 你不能打权杖钻石的主意 - 为什么不能?
- You can't nick the Crown Jewels. - Why not?
为什么?我会告诉你为什么不能
Why not?I'll tell you why not.
因为那是没有爱国心的开始
Because it's unpatriotic for a start.
另外,我可不能想像...
Besides which,I don't fancy being banged up...
在以后的300年内都被吊在伦敦塔上
in the Tower of London for the next 300 years.
- 这一次,我觉得Danny或许讲到重点了 - 耶,谢谢,Stacie
- For once,I think Danny may have a point. - Yeah,thank you,Stacie.
你的"这一次"是什么意思?
What do you mean "for once"?
如果我们被抓住了 他们会把钥匙扔掉的,是不是?
If we get caught,they'll throw away the key,won't they?
完全正确.我真是迫不及待要去监狱了 睡都睡不着
Exactly.I'm too pretty to go to prison.I'll never get any sleep.
算我老派吧.但我会让大家避免被抓住的
Call me old-fashioned,but I was hoping to avoid getting caught.
我们在说的可是一场世纪的犯罪
We're talking about the crime of the century.
有一队私人收藏家愿意付出...
There's a band of private collectors who are willing to pay...
小小的金钱把非洲之星第一 加入到他们的收藏中
a small fortune to add the First Star of Africa to their collection.
- 我们能找到他们吗? - 已经在进行中了
- Can we find them? - All in hand.
非洲之星第一
The First Star of Africa.
530.2克拉.也被称为库利南1号...
530.2 carats.Also known as the Cullinan I...
1905年在南非发现的库利南钻石 被切割成9块后...
because it's the largest of the nine stones cut from the Cullinan diamond...
这是最大的一块,因此得名
discovered in South Africa in 1905.
现在被镶在英国国王的权杖上
It's now set in the head of the Royal Scepter.
无价之宝
It is priceless.
老家在伦敦塔里
Home is the Tower of London.
历史上只有一次对权杖钻石进行过偷窃
There has only ever been one attempt to steal the Crown Jewels.
是Colonel Blood在1671年偷的
And that was by Colonel Blood in 1671.
- 他怎么样了? - 失败
- What happened to him? - He failed.
很好,那我们要做什么?游过护城河还是去攀登碉堡?
Great,so what are we gonna do?Swim the moat or scale the battlements?
不需要.国王的权杖要被搬动了...
No need.The Royal Scepter's being moved...
给了我们一生唯一一次的机会
giving us a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
它为什么会被搬动呢?
Why is it being moved?
现在皇家珠宝商正在对它进行清洗...
Right now it's being cleaned by the Royal Jewelers...
- 然后又会被搬动 - 去哪里?
- and after that it'll be moved again. - Where?
市政厅艺廊正在举办一次非洲展览...
The Guildhall Art Gallery is holding a major African exhibition...
来配合英联邦首脑会议
to coincide with the Commonwealth summit.
从后天开始...
It starts the day after tomorrow...
而这颗非洲之星就是中心装饰品
and the Star of Africa is to be the centerpiece.
好了.想想吧
All right.Think of it.
本世纪最伟大的一次记录,或是最后一次
The biggest score of this century or the last.
某些会在100年,甚至200年 以后还被记住的事情
Something that will be remembered 100,even 200 years from now.
一切我懂的,一切我所学到的 都在等着这一时刻
Everything I know,everything I've learned has been waiting for this moment.
没有比这更大的东西会再出现在我们面前
Nothing this big will ever come our way again.
而不利的是,如果我们被抓住了...
The downside is,if we get caught...
我们都会在监狱里面待上很长时间
we all go to prison for a very long time.
- 你还好吗,Mick? - 是啊,就那样吧
- You all right,Mick?You on your own? - Yeah,looks that way.
干杯
Cheers.
如果我不够了解你,我会说你在生气
If I didn't know better,I'd say you were sulking.
真的吗?
Really?
你在期盼什么?
What did you expect?
你要求他们把余生都压在这一次上
You asked them to put the rest of their lives on the line.
的确是
Yes,I did.
你掷骰子,他们紧紧盯着.就这样
You rolled the dice,they came up snake eyes.It happens.
是啊
Yep.
就告诉我一件事情
Just tell me one thing.
为什么?
Why?
因为300年来没有一个人敢对此进行尝试
Because no one has ever dared attempt anything this big for 300 years.
- 就这样? - 对于我来说,是的
- And that's it? - For me,yes.
瞧,这是镇里最大的游戏
Look,this is the biggest game in town.
如果我们不干,我们还能干什么
If we're not here,we're not anywhere.
我可以了解
I can see that.
你瞧,Mickey...
You see,Mickey...
之前我有我自己的顾虑...
I had my doubts earlier...
但你可以把我算在里面
but you can count me in.
谢谢,Danny.一语值千金
Thanks,Danny.That's worth a lot.
但如果没有Stacie和Ash的话还是不行
But this can't happen without Stacie and Ash.
真高兴听到你这么说
Glad to hear it.
- 他生气了吗,Albert? - 我想是的,是啊
- Was he sulking,Albert? - I'm afraid so,yeah.
- 哦哦 - 我没有生气
- Diddums. - I was not sulking.
嗯,装的不错,看起来你自己承认了啊
Well,it worked,looks like you're getting your own way.
不,等等,拜托
No,now,wait a minute,come on.
这件事情对这里的任何人来说都 是件大事...
This thing is far too big for anyone to be here...
比他们想做的任何事情都要大
for any other reason than they want to be.
你现在可不能反悔了
You can't bottle it now.
啊哦,一开始他生气,而现在他却 想收手不干
Cor blimey,first he sulks,now he's trying to back out.
我没有要收手,但是...
I'm not backing out,but...
如果我们要做的话,我们需要万分小心
if we do this,we do it with our eyes open.
嘿,如果我们不能...
Hey,if we can't do it...
还有谁能?
who can?
- Eddie - 记在账单上
- Eddie. - On the tab.
那么,对你们这群家伙来说或 这次是要转变方向了?
So,is this a change of direction for you boys?
- 你们现在成小偷了? - 只是想赚点生活费,Benny
- You're thieves now? - Just trying to earn a living,Benny.
跟我说说吧.这里不会再有正直的骗子了
Tell me about it,there are no honest crooks anymore.
每个人都企图占你便宜
Everyone tries to screw you.
我,我被占便宜的次数比妓女接的客还多
Me,I've been screwed more times than a coachload of hookers.
我看你说话还是很间接明了的啊,Benjamin
I see you still have a wonderful way with words,Benjamin.
不要跟我说简洁明了,Stroller先生
Don't talk to me about words,Mr.Stroller.
握握手就可以了
Time was a handshake was enough.
现在,大家都像14岁的小毛头 带着没剔干净的鼻毛...
Now,everyone's 14,with spots and rings in their noses...
用天花乱坠的说辞来欺骗你
all using fancy words to screw you.
"这个的5%,那个的两成"
"Five percent of this.Two pints of that."
"钱的10%下个星期三就付给你"
"Ten pence in the pound and pay you next Wednesday."
- 是啊,这个世界已经大不同了 - 就是这样
- Yeah,it's a different world. - That it is.
我?我拥有的已经足够了 明年,我就会把所有的都变卖
Me?I've had enough.Next year,I sell up.
让其他人去被占便宜吧
Let someone else get screwed.
那么.伟大的Mickey Bricks 和Albert Stroller
So.The great Mickey Bricks and Albert Stroller.
叫我中国佬吧,但我猜 你们没有一大包的汽车无线电
Call me a Chinaman but my guess is you don't have a bag full of car radios.
- 不是的 - 那到底是什么?
- Not quite. - So what is it?
权杖钻石?
The Crown Jewels?
告诉我你们不是真的要
Please tell me you're not serious.
我们要找的是一些私人收藏家 的秘密标价
What we're looking for are a few select private collectors to put in sealed bids.
- 一场拍卖? - 赢家获得所有的
- An auction? - Winner takes all.
我有多少时间准备?
How long have I got?
我们找到了为那家展览馆 做清理的公司
We've found the cleaning company who has the contract for the gallery.
他们雇佣东欧的工人
They employ mostly Eastern European workers.
- 你是说会便宜些 - 差不多
- You mean cheap. - Precisely.
你今晚就开始.那些是详细资料
And you start tonight.Those are the details.
好的
All right.
- 哈? - 是我
- Hello? - It's me.
- Benny,你有什么可以告诉我的? - 不简单啊
- Benny,what have you got for me? - It wasn't easy.
我不得不亲自告诉你 我觉得你们太愚蠢了
I have to say that personally,I think you're insane.
但如果你们成功了 我就能帮你们找到5个出价者
But if you pull it off,I've got five bidders lined up.
都是最一流的
All topnotch.
我就知道你是干这个的不二人选
I knew you were the man for the job.
密封的标价单会送到你的旅馆去
Sealed bids will be delivered to your hotel.
好的,Benny,我会去接收的
Okay,Benny,I'll be in touch.
- 怎么样? - 我们开始吧
- Well? - We are on.
谢谢.实在是太好了.不
Thank you.That's blinding.No.
- 不.相信我,非常感谢 - Danny,你在干吗?
- No.Believe me,thank you very much. - Danny,what are you doing?
- 电话奖励,一分钟一英镑 - 什么?
- Premium phone line,50 quid a minute. - What?
我设置了这些线路中的一条 每次有人拨打这个号码...
I set up one of these lines.Every time somebody phones this number...
我的口袋里就会进账1英镑
I get 50 quid in me pocket.
但你怎么让别人打你这个号码呢?
But how are you going to get people to phone the number?
不,瞧,这就是我天才的地方
No,listen,this is where the genius comes in.
因为我无需这样,你瞧
'Cause I don't have to,you see.
我所要做的,就是我借个电话打 这个号码
All I got to do,yeah,is I borrow a phone and I call the number.
是的,然后它们会认为我花了10 先令的话费...
Yeah,then they think I'm making a 10p call...
但我口袋里却已经进账了1英镑
but I'm getting 50 big ones in me pocket.
- Danny - 是的,Mickey
- Danny. - Yeah,Mickey.
你不让我用信用卡的
You did stop me using the credit cards.
- 他们会留下罪证的 - 但它们管用
- They were very bad copies. - But they did work.
我们已经被一家餐馆扔出来了
We got thrown out of a restaurant.
好吧,你对的.但我还是有些吃住的问题
Granted,everyone,but I had a few teething troubles.
Danny,我劝你最好专心到我们 手上的工作中
Danny,I would much rather you focused on the job in hand.
我一直关心的,伙计们,我关心的 这只是我的一点点副业而已
I'm focused,gang,I'm focused.This is just a little sideline.
我要弄点点钱在你让我们被捕后 还能买一些烟草
Make a little bit of money to buy some tobacco when you get us all arrested.
Eddie,我能借用下你的电话吗,伙计?给我老妈打个电话
Eddie,can I borrow your phone,mate?Just got to phone me old mom.
哈,妈妈?
Hello,Mom?
我会看着你
I'll be watching you.
- 我刚泡了一壶茶 - 哦,谢谢
- I've just made a pot of tea. - Yes,thank you.
我马上就干完了
I will just finish my work.
你会把清漆都磨掉的 你还在磨
You'll wear the varnish off,you polish it any more.
但我想干得更好一些
But I want to do a good job.
是的.但如果你喝杯茶后会干得更好
Yes,and you'll do a better job with a cup of tea inside you.
我5分钟就好
I be five minute.
Lily
Lily.
- 那里怎么了? - 有某个特别的展览
- What is happening in there? - Some kind of special exhibition.
非常机密的
All very hush- hush.
- 练习练习脚步 - 那音乐呢?
- Practicing a few moves. - And the music?
给我一些情绪
Get me in the mood.
- 对汤姆克鲁斯很管用,不是吗? - 好吧
- It worked for Tom Cruise,didn't it? - Okay.
我还没有进过里面的密室 但从我了解到的情况来看...
I haven't got in the chamber yet,but from what I've seen...
他们安装了行动探测器,激光 探测器,闭路电视...
they've got motion detectors,lasers,CCTV...
压力垫和带有时间锁的钢制门
pressure pads and a steel door with a time lock.
- 看来是双重保险啊 - 你要说的重点是什么?
- Belt and braces security then. - So what's the bottom line?
对我们来说,如果他们把它放在 伦敦塔里,说不定还简单些
It would have been easier if they'd kept it in the Tower of London.
没事的,我们有个在职的蜘蛛侠
It'll be okay,we've got Spiderman on board.
是啊,你们尽管笑话我吧
Yeah.Let's all have a good laugh.
听着,我就是唯一那个适合的人
Listen,I'll be the only one who's match fit,okay.
是的,对于压力垫我们无可奈何
Yeah,there's nothing we can do about the pressure pads.
我们只能绕过它行动
We'll have to work round them.
最大的问题会是那扇门
The biggest problem,though,will be the doors.
它们一旦被关闭后,只能到明天 早上才能打开
Once they're shut,there's no other way of opening them until the morning.
- 我们能通过其他途径进去吗? - 不.这是个密封的房间
- Can we get in any other way? - No.It's a sealed room.
- 没有窗户.所以他们选择了这里 - 我们能挖地道进去吗?
- No windows.That's why they chose it. - Can we tunnel in?
不,那会触动移动探测器
No,that would set off the motion detectors.
没有办法能把它们设置旁路吗?
And there's no way of bypassing them?
是的.如果有,那我也还没有发现
Yeah.If there is,I haven't found it.
Ash,你的意思就是说 我们应该放弃这次行动?
So what are you saying,Ash?We should just call the whole thing off?
不.再给我一点时间,我会找出方法的
No.Just give me a bit more time.I'll see what I can do.
同时...
In the meantime...
我上班要迟到了
I'm late for work.
是的
Yeah.
我再打给你吧
I'm gonna have to call you back.
你好啊,Benny
Hello,Benny.
这是在你的仓库里面找到的东西清单
This is an inventory of what was found in your warehouse.
而这是失窃报告的物品清单...
And this is a list of items reported stolen...
就是在过去7天左右伦敦市郊失窃的物品
in the Greater London area over the past seven days.
你可以看出来它们是一致的
As you can see they're virtually identical.
我都是通过正规渠道买进来的
I bought every item there in good faith.
这样的话,你就应该有收据,发票
In which case you'll have receipts,invoices.
提供者的姓名和地址
Names and addresses of suppliers.
- 我们遇到火灾了 - 哦,是的
- We had a fire. - Oh,yes.
的确是
Of course you did.
犯罪记录
Crime report.
有一整箱的电脑装备...
A container- Ioad of computer equipment...
在三个星期之前被人从码头偷走了
was stolen from the docks three weeks ago.
昨天早上被我们找到
They found the container yesterday morning.
有人试图烧毁它
Someone had tried to burn it.
这年头的小孩,无组织无纪律
Kids these days.No discipline.
火被扑灭了
The fire went out.
我们采集了指纹...
We dusted for prints...
你永远也猜不到我们找到了什么
and you'll never guess what we found.
完全匹配
Perfect match.
一目了然,Benny
Bang to rights,Benny.
- 会判多久,Wells先生? - 根据你的记录,15年
- How long,Mr.Wells? - With your form,fifteen years.
如果你认罪,或许是判12年
You take a guilty,you might get 12.
那么?
Well?
等等
Wait.
- 做个交易如何? - 什么样的交易?
- What about a deal? - What kind of deal?
最近会有一起权杖钻石的抢劫
The imminent robbery of the Crown Jewels.
- 你看看有多么宏伟... - 你说了7次了
- You saw how magnificent... - You said it seven times.
- 不 - Morgan先生
- No. - Mr.Morgan.
对不起打搅你,管理人员想知道...
I'm sorry to bother you,only the manager wondered...
你们是否可以付一下最近的账单?
whether you could bring your account up- to-date?
- 已经是一大笔钱了 - 哦,是啊
- It is rather a lot. - Yeah,it is.
- 我没有 - 你有
- I didn't have that. - You did.
- 你有吗? - 我没有,我不喜欢...
- Did you have that? - I didn't,I don't like...
- 那谁有? - 够了,这不是问题
- Who had that? - Enough.It's not a problem.
嘿
Hey.
把你的手收住吧,伙计 就放在那里,我来搞定
Put your hand in there,mate.Keep it in there,I'll get this.
- 谢谢 - 没事,不客气
- Thank you. - All right,you're very welcome.
瞧,亲爱的.你在刷卡的时候...
Listen,love,while you put that through the old switcherooney...
- 我能用你的电话吗? - 当然
- can I use your phone? - Of course.
给我老妈打个电话
Got to phone me old mom.
你好,妈妈?
Hello,Mom?
你不应该在这里的
You shouldn't be in here.
但我必须处理一下地板
But I have to do floors.
不是在这里,亲爱的 他们会带其他人过来的
Not in here,sweetheart.They're bringing other people in.
对不起
I am sorry.
看来我必须看着你了.来吧
I can see I'll have to keep an eye on you.Come on.
来喝杯茶吧.你可以来试试我的波旁茶
Come and have a cuppa.You can try my Bourbons.
- Mick - 嘿
- Mick. - Hey.
- 怎么样了? - 我满脚的水泡
- How's it going? - I've got blisters on me blisters.
- 有所得必有所失 - 是啊,是的.谢谢
- No gain without pain. - Yeah,right.Thank you.
瞧,我想我有办法了 门上有个保险装置
Look,I think I've got it.There's a safety feature on the door.
里面时间锁上有个面板 如果有人被锁在里面就能起作用
The time lock's got a panel on the inside,in case anyone gets locked in.
我们能利用这个吗?
So can we use that?
如果我们中有人能在他们关门 之前就在里面
If we can get someone inside before they close it.
嘿,你们是不是该回家了?
Hey,haven't you lot got any homes to go to?
- 再有一会儿就好了,Eddie - 是啊,拜托
- Just a few more minutes,Eddie. - Yeah,come on.
- 我可要去睡个好觉了 - 是啊,我也马上就睡了
- I need my beauty sleep. - Yeah,I'll second that.
- 你要喝杯吧? - 你搞得定吗?
- Do you want a drink? - Won't you be lucky?
Eddie,我只是想说...
Eddie,I just want to say...
我真的很感激你在我和Ash 一直在工作的时候还在坚持
that I really appreciate you hanging on while Ash and I work something through.
- 是啊,我知道,Mick,但真的很晚了... - 瞧,我来告诉你,好吗
- Yeah,I know,Mick,but it's really late... - Look,I'll tell you what,okay.
我们只要再喝一杯...
We'll just have one more drink...
我保证,我们真的很快就能搞定了
and I promise,we'll be out of your hair really soon.
你看呢?
What do you say?
拜托,我们1点就走
Come on,we'll be gone by 1:00.
但现在已经...
No,but it's gone on....
我发誓现在的时间应该比这个要晚
I could have sworn it was later than that.
- 好吧,你们再喝一杯 - 你太棒了
- Go on,then,one more. - You're a star.
好了,继续.跟我说说这个安全装置
Right,come on,tell me about this safety feature.
长官?
Sir?
- DS Hodges? - 是的,长官
- DS Hodges? - Yes,sir.
你的档案告诉我你曾经调查过去年的一个案子
Your DI tells me you were working on a case last year.
Michael Stone?
瞧,我们一直在监视Stone
Look,we had Stone under surveillance.
但他不知为何发现了
But he found out somehow.
然后弄了另外一个骗子装扮成了警察
And drafted in another grifter to impersonate a police officer.
案子就搞砸了?
And the case collapsed?
Stone的人介入了调查,长官
Stone's man ran the investigation,sir.
对你来说一定非常难堪
Must have been very embarrassing for you.
对这个部门来说都很难堪,长官
It was embarrassing for the whole department,sir.
- DCI Mullens因为这件事情而丢了工作 - 是吗,现在?
- DCI Mullens lost his job because of it. - Did he,now?
那么....
So....
跟我说说Stone
Tell me about Stone.
- 骗子艺术家... - 不.我知道他做了些什么
- Long con artist... - No.I know what he does.
跟我说说这个人
Tell me about the man.
Mickey Stone是很独特的
Mickey Stone is unique.
他想的和我们不一样 你无法对他进行揣测
He doesn't think like we do.You can't second-guess him.
他给人的印象像是很随意地 走一步算一步
He gives the impression that he's making it all up as he goes along.
不
No.
但每件事情都计划过,非常精确
But everything is planned,precise.
- 为什么是我? - 你抽到了最短的麦杆
- Why me? - You drew the short straw.
我要申述
I demand a recount.
你要推我下去的时候...
So when you gonna push me...
他会把一堆乱七八糟的事情放在一起...
He puts together complicated...
一堆看起来毫无关系的事情 根本想不到有关
and seemingly unrelated events,impossible to unravel.
服务员,我要一个这个
Waiter,I'll have one of those.
但所有的都指向一个大骗局
But all leading to the big con.
目标越大,他越喜欢
The higher the stakes,the more he likes it.
是的,要很长一段时间
Yes,it has been long.
你以为你抓住他的时候...
Just when you think you've got him...
我帮你找了份工作
I've got a job for you.
你坐着吗?
Are you sitting down?
- ...其实你没有 - 听起来,你像是个大粉丝
- ...you haven't. - You sound like a bit of a fan.
绝对不是,长官,他让我看起来 像是个无能的白痴
Hardly,sir,he made me look like an incompetent idiot.
如果能让你找回自我的话如何?
Then how would you like to get your own back?
哦,上帝!对不起
Oh,God!Sorry.
我跟你说,我绝对有些感冒了
I tell you now,I've definitely caught something.
这件事情除非我们能先在展览馆里面安插好人手
Okay,this thing isn't going to work
否则就无法进行...
unless we can get someone inside the gallery...
特别是在门被锁上以后要在展室里面有人
and in the exhibition room when the doors are locked.
一旦夜间门被关闭,只能从里面打开
Once they're locked for the night,the doors can only be opened from the inside.
- 而这就是你要进去的地方 - 怎么进?
- Which is where you come in. - How?
Ash
Ash.
我们可以从空中着手以避开压力垫
We can get round the pressure pads by going over the top.
关键问题是,门的时间锁旁边围绕着...
The main problem,though,aside from the time lock on the door...
激光探测器和动作探测器
will be the lasers and the motion detectors.
就像我说的,我们没有办法可以设置旁路...
Like I said,there's no way we can bypass them...
一旦我们步入房间它们就会引发警报
and they'll set the alarms off as soon as we set foot in the room.
- 解决办法呢? - 至今看来唯一可以解决的办法就是...
- Solution? - The only way round it as far as I can see...
- 切断电源 - 会让警报关闭吗?
- is to cut the power. - Won't that set the alarms off?
是的,但如果我们在马路外面做...
Yeah,but if we do it outside somewhere in the road...
我们会破坏整个街道的电力
we'll knock out the whole street.
- 那所有的警报就都会消失 - 聪明
- There'll be alarms going off everywhere. - Smart.
同时,我们就有30秒的时间来 通过动作探测器...
During that time,we'll have 30 seconds to cover up the motion detectors...
到达门的面板处,关闭激光探测器
and get to the door panel to stop the lasers from coming back on.
- 时间够吗? - 只能那么多时间
- Will that be enough time? - It'll have to be.
一旦有电力恢复,激光和所有 警报设备就会重新开启
Once the genny kicks in,the lasers and everything else will be back on.
闭路电视呢?
CCTV?
我可以在停电的时候重新 设置录像源
I can re-route those at source during the blackout.
- 很好 - 那么,我要做什么?
- Good. - So,what do I have to do then?
在我们打开那扇门之前,必须关闭...
The motion detectors and the lasers have to be disabled from the inside...
动作探测器和激光探测器
before we open the door.
展览有5个主要的负责人
The exhibition has five main exhibitors.
最重要的那个人就是Joyce Martin
The biggest of which is Joyce Martin.
你专门研究哪个部分?
So what is your area of expertise?
我绝对的崇拜从尼日尔三角区 来的Urhobo的那块
I absolutely adore the Urhobo pieces from the Niger Delta.
尤其是Iphri版画
Particularly the Iphri carved figures.
但是,出了传统的之外...
But,aside from the traditional...
我还对一些更加现代的部分感兴趣...
I've always had a deep affection for some of the more contemporary pieces...
例如Bruce Onobrakpeya的环氧树脂版画
such as Bruce Onobrakpeya's epoxy resin etchings.
太让人着迷了
Completely stunning.
谁用了我的电话?
Who's been using my phone?
- Mick,我能说句话吗? - 当然可以
- Mick,can I say something? - Yeah,of course.
- 我现在感觉真的很不好 - 为什么?
- I've got a really bad feeling about this. - How so?
- 我不知道,只是觉得... - 有勇无谋?
- I don't know,it just feels... - Foolhardy?
是的,有那么点意思
Yeah,that'll do for a start.
Ash,这是我们做过的最大的案子
Ash,this is the biggest thing we've ever done.
- 不可能那么简单 - 是啊,但有太多我们会失手的地方
- It was never gonna be easy. - Yeah,but there's so much can go wrong.
我知道,但不会的.不会的
I know,but it won't.It won't.
好吧,说说
Okay,say it.
不要让我失手,我不是在指责你
Don't get me wrong,I'm not criticizing you.
我知道你是个惊人的天才
I think you're a flaming genius.
- 但我必须说出我所想的 - 你觉得这是个馊主意
- But I have to say what I think. - And you think this is a bad idea.
那是我心里的想法
It's what me gut says.
好啊,亲爱的.新面孔啊.你怎么样?
Hello,sweetheart.New face.How you doing?
非常感谢,再见
Thank you very much.Goodbye.
标书在里面
Bids are in.
Albie打电话来,一切已经就绪
And Albie called,everything is set his end.
Joyce Martin?
她让我负责在展会继续展览的事宜
She's put me in charge of the items going on show at the exhibition.
那么我们准备好了吗?
So are we good to go?
是的,明天晚上
Yeah.Tomorrow night.
钻石,明天早上会在...
The diamond,it'll be delivered to the gallery...
全副武装的警卫下运送到展览馆
under armed guard tomorrow morning.
我们知道Mickey Bricks和他的小组...
We know that Mickey Bricks and his team...
想偷钻石
are going to steal it.
这是第一次我们有个良好的开端
This is the first time that we've got a head start.
他们不可能知道我们已经盯上他们了
There is no way they can know we're onto them.
- 我们必须利用这一点 - 好的,我们知道他们很聪明
- We must use that. - Okay,we know they're smart.
所以不要监视
So no surveillance.
我不想冒着被他们看出 这次行动风吹草动的险
I won't risk them getting wind of this operation.
那就表示我们只是简单的看着展览馆...
Which means that we simply watch the gallery...
等待他们的行动
and wait for them to make their move.
- 所有人都明白了吗? - 是的,老大
- Does everyone understand that? - Yes,guv.
这个小组太多次让我们看起来像傻瓜了
This team has made us look like fools too many times.
这次轮到我们
This time it's our turn.
我找到了一个地方来割断电力设备 但还有个问题
I've found a place to cut off the power,but there's a problem.
- 什么? - 我一次不能出现在两个地方
- What? - I can't be in two places at once.
在电源断开的同时...
At the same time the power is being cut off...
有人必须对闭路电视的录像 做个重录
someone has to be re-routing the feed to the CCTV cameras.
你不能教某人来做吗?
Can't you show someone how to do that?
不,最好是我做 不过可以找人来切断电源
No,it's best if I do it.Someone else can do the electricity.
- 好吧,教Danny - 我?不
- Okay,show Danny. - Me?No.
不,我对配线一窍不通
No,I have trouble wiring a plug.
没事的.我会直接教你 我们可以用对讲机
It's all right.I'll talk you through it.We can use walkie-talkies.
- 好吧,我来 - Stacie,你怎么进入展览馆?
- Okay,I'll do it. - Stacie,how you getting on at the gallery?
我已经找到了一个好地方
I've found a piece that's perfect.
- Albert? - 所有一切就绪
- Albert? - Everything will be ready.
好的,展览明天开幕 我们先睡个好觉吧
Okay,the exhibition opens tomorrow.So let's get some sleep.
我们会到这里.在控制室里面有4个警卫
We'll come in here.There'll be four guards in the control room.
一个会一直在巡逻
One will be doing his rounds.
没有换班的空闲,所以我们只能穿过他
Yeah,there's no set time,so the chances are we'll have to get past him.
这个搞定了...
That done...
Ash就会给Danny发出信号切断电源...
Ash will give the signal to Danny to cut the power...
可以让我们有30秒的时间来 重新录制闭路电视...
which will give us 30 seconds to re-route the CCTV...
而Stacie则负责她的事情
and for Stacie to do her thing.
你必须在电力恢复之前到达门口
You must get to the door before the emergency power kicks in.
- 好的 - 否则你就会被激光探测器逮到
- Okay. - Or you'll be trapped by the lasers.
你们一切都搞定后 我们应该在另外一边
When you've done that,we should be on the other side.
我要走了
I'd better go.
- Albert呢? - 二层楼
- Albert? - Second floor.
你们必须准时
And you must be on time.
我们会的.还有什么问题吗?
We will.Any questions?
- 没了 - 我们开始吧
- No. - Then let's go.
谢谢你听我说,亲爱的
Thanks for listening,sweetheart.
无线静音,直到进一步的指示
Radio silence until further notice.
清洁公司
Cleaning team.
准时到
On time.
- 你好了吗,Mick? - 是的
- You okay,Mick? - Yeah.
把那个放回我的包里
Put that back in me bag.
好的
All right.
或许他们不是今天晚上做
Maybe they're not going to do it tonight.
现在我该怎么做?
Now what do I do?
- 好了 - 很好
- Okay. - All right.
- 来吧,亲爱的.我们走 - 好的
- Come on,baby.There we go. - All right.
准备好了,Mick
We're on,Mick.
现在我们会录一会儿这个 然后通过线路回录到带子中
Now we'll tape it for a while and then feed the tape through on a loop.
好了
Okay.
- Danny,来吧 - 准备好了.结束
- Danny,come in. - Ready,over.
好点.应该够了
Okay,that should be enough.
Danny?
你把盒子放到适当的位置了吗?
Have you got the box in place?
坚持下
Hang on.
是的,我已经放好了
Yeah,I got the box in place.
当你夹上夹子的时候 不会发生任何事情
When you put the clips on,nothing will happen.
10秒以后,电力系统会被切断
Then after 10 seconds,the power will cut out.
把鳄鱼夹夹在两个...
Take the crocodile clips and clip them both on the...
Vinny,你在哪呢,亲爱的?
Vinny,where are you,mate?
我选择在Chapel Road 19号,West One
I've got a pick up at 19 Chapel Road,West One.
哈,你在我的频道里
Hello,you're on my frequency.
我觉得你会发现事实上你是在 我的频道里,亲爱的
I think you'll find you're on mine actually,darling.
就下下线吧,你个昏睡的母牛
Just get off the line,you dozy cow.
你是想用那个频道跟我说话 呢还是想叫辆出租车
Don't you use that tone with me or you won't get a cab.
我不要出租车,赶紧下线
I don't want a bleeding cab.Just get off the line.
- 那是谁,Mary? - 一个乱七八糟的小混蛋
- Who's that,Mary? - Some bloke messing about.
- Danny? - Ash?
总是红色的.总是红色的,是不是?
It's always the red.It's always red,isn't it?
来吧.或是蓝的?是蓝的吗?
Come on.Or is it blue?Is it blue?
蓝的还是红的?
Blue or red?
红的
Red.
如果...
What the....
好孩子.来吧,Stace 你有30秒的时间
Good boy.Come on,Stace.You got 30 seconds.
12秒,13秒
12 elephant,13 elephant.
16秒
16 elephant.
20秒
20 elephant.
20. 21
Twenty.Twenty-one.
25,26 秒
25,26 elephant.
30.妈的
30.Shit.
很好.好了
Good.Okay.
闭路电视好了.都重新回来了
CCTV returned.It's all back up again.
- 一切完好 - 好的
- All secured. - Okay.
哈?
Hello?
希望Stacie搞定了她的事情
Let's hope Stacie's done her stuff.
- 好了,走吧? - 好的
- Right,let's go? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
外部电力切断.不只是展览馆 整个地区全部断电
External power cut.It wasn't just the gallery,the whole sector was out.
安全方面?
Security?
紧急电力开启,警报已经重新设置
The emergency power is on and alarms have re-armed.
你想做什么?
What do you want to do?
坚守岗位
Hold your positions.
我想知道他们是否在那里
I want to know if they're in there.
她在干吗?她现在应该已经开门了
What's she doing?She should have opened the door by now.
一定出了些问题
Something must have gone wrong.
来吧,Stacie
Come on,Stacie.
你怎么了?
What kept you?
看好压力垫
Watch the pressure pads.
最重要的一点就是压力垫
Everything beyond this point is a pressure pad.
如果我们碰到了,就会触动警报,明白吗?
If we touch them,the alarms go off,all right?
- 你准备好了,Mick? - 来吧
- You ready,Mick? - Let's go.
Stace
Stace.
继续
Carry on.
下
Down.
停
Stop.
你好,请转新闻部,谢谢
Hello,news desk,please.
升高
Lift.
好了,下
Okay,down.
停
Stop.
- 好的,到现在为止都很好 - 是啊
- Okay,any time now would be good. - Yeah.
为剪贴簿来一张
One for the scrapbook.
怎么又来了一辆清洁工的卡车
That's the cleaner's van again.
妈的,他们一定在第一辆卡车上
Shit,they must have been in the first van.
- 走 - 拉警报!拉警报!
- Go. - Hit the alarms!Hit the alarms!
我就知道
I knew it.
- 你他妈是谁? - 我是时代周刊的
- Who the hell are you? - I'm with The Times.
我们刚刚收到了一起入室抢劫的电话
We just received a call about a break-in.
- 把她弄出去! - 哦,好吧,就一分钟
- Get her out! - Yeah,okay,just one minute.
- 你觉得被偷了多少东西? - 请
- How many do you think were involved? - Please.
有什么意见吗?
Any ideas?
在外面待着
Stay out.
他们不可能通过其他出口逃离
There's no way they got out through any of the exits.
屋顶
The roof.
嘿
Hey.
妈的
Shit.
安静
Quiet.
你们介意吗?
Do you mind?
裙子
Dress.
他们消失了
They disappeared.
- 障碍物呢? - 他们现在可以在任何地方
- Roadblocks? - They could be anywhere now.
好吧
Okay.
- 没有关系 - 什么?
- It doesn't matter. - What?
想想
Think about it.
我们知道是他们
We know it was them.
但他们却不知道我们已经知道了
But they have no way of knowing that.
- 什么意思? - 他们不知道我们在找他们
- Which means? - They don't know we're looking for them.
我用一年的薪水和你打赌...
I will bet you one year's salary...
- 他们会重新回到酒店 - 他们不会那么愚蠢的
- they turn up back at the hotel. - They wouldn't be that stupid.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
他们要关心的是如何滚出去了
As far as they're concerned,they've got clean away.
- 我还是觉得他们会远走高飞 - 走着瞧
- I still think they'll be long gone. - We'll see.
老大?
Guv?
是的
Yes.
一辆黑色的出租车要从你们旁边经过
Black cab just about to pass you,
有5个人在里面,我觉得就是他们
five people inside.I think it's them.
看好你的位置
Hold your positions.
等我的信号
Wait for my signal.
所以我说这是个美好的夜晚
That is what I call a great night.
我不知道你们还要干吗 但我这个老家伙可要睡觉了
I don't know about the rest of you,the old man's gonna hit the sack.
- 是啊,我想我还是跟你一起吧 - 真的吗?
- Yeah,I think I'll join you. - Really?
不,我不是说要和你一起睡 我要睡我自己的床
No.I don't mean I'm gonna join you.I'm gonna have me own bed.
- 我以为你不介意呢 - 我介意,我爱你,Albert
- I had no idea you cared. - I do care,I love you,Albert.
- 你说你爱我.哦,我的上帝! - 闭嘴
- You said you loved me.Oh,my God! - Shut up.
听着,你们各回各家吧 我可要去喝一杯
Listen,you lot do what you want,all right,'cause I'm gonna get a drink.
我这两天可实在太受伤了
'Cause I've had a very traumatic couple of days.
哦,拜托,我跟你一起
Come on,then,I'll keep you company.
注意,注意
Eye,eye.
站住.不许动
Stand still.Don't move.
- 怎么了? - 你们被捕了
- What's going on? - You're all under arrest.
为了什么?
For what?
涉嫌偷窃
Suspicion of theft.
对不起.我不明白你在说什么
I'm sorry,I have no idea what you're talking about.
把他们带走
Take them away.
这里,请,先生
This way,please,sir.
...如果审讯的时候没有老实回答...
...it may harm your defense if you do not mention when questioned...
你可以继续在法庭上申述
something that you later rely on in court.
但你所说的一切都会作为陈堂证供
Anything you do say may be given in evidence.
我是警察局长的朋友 如果你打电话给他的话
I'm a friend of the police commissioner.If you'd just call him.
一目了然,Mickey,派对结束了
Bang to rights,Mickey,party's over.
排好队等着
Wait in line.
我要跟我的辩护律师说话
I want to speak to my brief.
会有时间的.就站在那里
In good time,just stand there.
好了,谁先来?
All right,who's first?
他以涉嫌发生在今晚
He's been arrested on suspicion of theft...
10:30分在市政展览厅的偷窃罪名被捕
at the Guildhall Gallery at 10:30 this evening.
- 姓名? - Ashley Morgan
- Name? - Ashley Morgan.
- 生日? - 21/7/60.
- Date of birth? - 21/7/60.
- 住址? - 列克星敦旅馆
- Address? - The Lexington Hotel.
把你口袋中的东西拿出来,好吗?
Empty your pockets out,will you,please?
你是不是忘了什么东西了?
You've forgotten something?
- 把这个冲出来 - 长官
- Get this developed. - Sir.
脱下你的领带
Take your tie off.
第3个
Number three.
没有在列克星敦旅馆那么舒服 但你也没有选择了
Not quite as comfortable as the Lexington,but you'll have to make do.
好了,谁是下一个?
All right,who's next?
警长刚刚证实...
Police chiefs have just confirmed...
有5个嫌疑犯已经被拘捕...
that five suspects have been detained for the theft...
罪名是盗窃世界著名的钻石,非洲之星
of one of the world's best known diamonds,the First Star of Africa.
无价之宝,被镶嵌在国王权杖上...
The priceless diamond,which usually adorns the Royal Scepter...
最近刚从伦敦塔运出,放置到...
was recently moved from the Tower of London,to be placed...
市政展览馆作为特别公众展出的中心展品
as the centerpiece in a special public exhibition at the Guildhall Gallery.
继续对Michael Stone的审讯
Resuming interview with Michael Stone.
早上9:13
9:13 a.m.
那么,Mickey,你已经有很多时间来思考了
So,Mickey,you've had a bit of time to think.
- 是啊 - 你有什么要告诉我们的吗?
- Yeah. - Is there anything you'd like to tell us?
- 无可奉告 - 那我会再问你一次
- Nothing springs to mind. - Then I will ask you again.
你能否告诉我昨天晚上 10:30的时候你在哪里?
Can you tell me again where you were at 10:30 last night?
- 我不太记得了 - 还没有到12个小时呢
- It's slipped my mind. - It's less than 12 hours ago.
是的,我知道.但我的记性不太好
Yeah,I know,I've got a terrible memory.
10:30?
我记起来了.不,又忘记了
I remember.No,it's gone again.
我真的很抱歉,但我的...
I'm terribly sorry,but my....
怎么说来着?记性 我的记性实在不好,你也看见了
What's the word?Memory.It isn't quite what it was,you see.
你在说什么?
What were you saying?
有什么苦工的机会吗?
Any chance of a fag?
抢劫?太可怕了 你抓住谁了吗?
A robbery?How thrilling.Have you caught anyone yet?
谢谢你,亲爱的
Thank you,sweetheart.
瞧,我真的不知道你在说什么,长官
Look,I really have no idea what you're talking about,Officer.
审讯暂停,上午9:18分
Interview suspended,9:18 a.m.
- 钻石在哪里,Mickey? - 可以这样吗?
- Where's the diamond,Mickey? - Is that allowed?
那该死的钻石到底在哪里?
Where's the bloody diamond?
什么?
What?
我能说句话吗,老大?
Can I have a word,guv?
你或许觉得你是清白的 但我知道就是你做的
You might think you're clever,but I know you did this.
我会把你关起来
And I'm going to put you away.
- 不管有没有钻石 - 长官?
- With or without the diamond. - Sir?
我想你最好看看这个
I think you better see this.
这是我们从Morgan的相机里得到的照片
It's the film we took from Morgan's camera.
测试.1,2,3,4.你们后面的能听得到我吗?
Testing.One,two,three,four.Can you hear me at the back?
女士们先生们,欢迎来到警局 英勇奖章颁发现场
Ladies and gentlemen,welcome to the Police Courage Awards.
请大家按位子坐好
Would you please make your way towards your seats.
典礼马上就开始.谢谢
And the ceremonies will begin very shortly.Thank you.
今晚要颁发的是新近设立的 市民奖项
And now the last of tonight's civilian awards goes to a late entry.
某人就在几天之前...
Someone who was brought to the Commissioner's attention...
引起了委员的注意
only a few days ago.
谢谢
Thank you.
服务员,我要一份这个
Waiter,I'll have one of those.
有一个人,不顾自身安危...
A man who,without any thought for his own safety...
挽救了一名年轻路人的生命
saved the life of a fellow rambler.
Michael Stone和那个他拯救了 的人,Daniel Blue
Michael Stone and the man who's life he saved,Daniel Blue.
我正在河边慢跑
I was leaning down.
看见了一只受伤的小鸭子
There was an injured duck,you see.
我正试图帮助...
So there I was just trying to help...
帮助这个可怜的小家伙 突然,我一失足...
just help the little fellow,when suddenly,I lost me footing...
等我能意识到的时候 我已经在水里了
and the next thing I knew,I was in the water.
- 为什么是我? - 你抽到了最短的麦杆
- Why me? - You drew the short straw.
我要申述
I demand a recount.
你推我下去的时候...
So when you gonna push me...
我快淹死了.几乎淹死了
I was drowning.Definitely drowning.
- 我不会游泳.救命 - 嘿
- I can't swim.Help. - Hey.
我的一生在眼前像电影一般放过...
My whole life started flashing before me...
我刚刚离开学校...
I'd just left school...
然后就感到有一双坚强的手把 我拉了起来
and I felt a strong hand pulling me up.
那就是他,那就是他
There he is,there he is.
那就是Stone先生
It was Mr.Stone.
他...
He...
救了我的命.谢谢
saved my life.Thank you.
没什么的
Doesn't mean anything.
在没有钻石这种情况下 我们没法逮捕他们
We've got nothing to place them at the scene and no diamond.
- 他们肯定藏起来了 - 那更糟糕
- They've hidden it. - It gets worse.
我们知道钻石在10:30被偷的时候 离典礼地有半英里
We know the diamond was stolen half a mile from the ceremony at 10:30.
看专员的手表
The Commissioner's watch.
上面是10:20
It says 10:20.
你忘了什么东西
You've forgotten something.
那....
That's....
那不可能
That's not possible.
而后只要在最后,在上面洒上一层薄粉
And then just at the end,they add the little sprinkles on top.
就做成了一杯摩卡咖啡
And that's what makes it a mochaccino.
- 你可以走了 - 我没听清?
- You're free to go. - I'm sorry?
我说,你可以走了
I said you're free to go.
好吧,但我突然想起来了,我那个时候在...
Okay.It's just come back to me,where I was...
把他弄出去
Get him out of here.
很高兴又见到你.很有意思
Nice to see you again.It's been fun.
事情还没有结束.你们还必须要转移钻石
It's not over yet.You still have to move the diamond.
而你转移的时候,我就等在那里
And when you do,I'll be there.
- 你都去哪里了? - 嘿
- Where have you been? - Hey.
那个可爱的押管警官 他让我用了他的电话
The nice custody sergeant,he let me use his phone.
拜托,我们还没搞定呢
Come on,we haven't got long.
英国中央情报部
CID.
你肯定?
Are you sure?
好的,谢谢
Okay,thank you.
长官
Sir.
我们找到钻石了
We've found the diamond.
太好了
Yes.
- 在哪里? - 还在展览馆里
- Where is it? - It's still at the gallery.
Doris,我们做得如何了?
Doris,how did we do?
根据你的要求,复制了5份
Five copies as ordered.
太好了,Lily,再来一张,谢谢
That's great,Lily,just one more,please.
我不懂了
I don't understand.
为什么惹了那么大的麻烦...
Why go to all this trouble...
却不拿走钻石?
and not even take the diamond?
英格兰政府一定对这次偷盗非常难堪
The British government are naturally very embarrassed by this theft.
所以Ml6不得不编造出一个故事 来挽回他们的颜面
So Ml6 has come up with a plan to invent a story to save face.
他们会说钻石已经找到了...
They'll say the diamond has been found...
犯罪者也已经被抓住
and the perpetrators caught.
然后他们会把一颗赝品放进权杖 并重新放入伦敦塔
They'll then put a replica into the Royal Scepter and replace it in the Tower.
是啊,我们期待着掩盖故事...
Yeah,we're expecting the cover-up story to hit the press...
就在今天晚些时候,你能看到的
some time later today,just so you know.
然后,我所要做的就是来问你的出价了 我能用你的电话吗?
So then,all that leaves me to do is to ask you,can I use your phone?
谢谢
Thank you.
你好啊,妈妈?
Hello,Mom?
警察吗?
Police?
我想报告一些被盗物品的下落
I'd like to report the whereabouts of some stolen goods.
- 你获得特赦了? - 正在着手处理
- You got your amnesty? - In writing.
那么Benny...
And Benny...
- 好好享受你的退休吧 - 我肯定会的
- enjoy your retirement. - I certainly will.
哦,你这小信的人啊
Oh,ye of little faith.
你瞧,这是场完美的骗局
You see,it's the perfect con.
没有犯罪行为,所以没有人会为此被捕
There's no crime,so there's nothing to be arrested for.
唯一的输家就是那5个贪婪的 猪头买了5个赝品钻石
And the only losers are five mugs greedy enough to buy five fake diamonds.
当他们发现他们被骗的时候...
And when they find out they've been conned...
又会向谁去说呢?
who are they gonna tell?
这些,净赚的钱
There it is,back of the net.
好吧,我们要先干一杯 为了Mickey Bricks干杯...
Right,this is a toast.A toast to Mickey Bricks...
- 一个不容置疑的伟大天才 - 值得任何荣誉
- who is without doubt,a bleeding genius. - Worthy of any of the greats.
我还是觉得他应该一开始就告诉我们
I still think he should have told us at the start.
冒的险是一样的.如果你被抓住了...
The risk was the same.If you got caught...
谁会相信你没有偷钻石 而只是简单把它移动了一下?
who would have believed you weren't stealing the diamond,simply moving it?
你要再看一下吗?
Will you take a look at that?
好人啊,Lily.她值得有些小运气
Nice one,Lily.She deserved a bit of luck.
是啊,太漂亮了,Ash 和这个一样漂亮的一件事情是...
Yeah,it's beautiful,Ash,nearly as beautiful as the fact...
我手机上已经被打了93分钟的电话...
that I've now clocked up 93 minutes on my phone line...
我总共收到了2,500便士
which comes to 2,500.
好极了
Right on.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 谁付的账单? - Danny
- Who paid the bill? - Danny.
- 用什么付的? - 信用卡
- With what? - Credit card.
- 请告诉我不是那样的 - 怎么了?
- Please tell me you didn't. - What?
警察在楼下...
The police are downstairs...
前台正在给他们看信用卡的收据
and the receptionist is showing them a credit card receipt.
所以,求你了,Danny,随便怎么样求你了...
So,please,Danny,pretty please with knobs on...
告诉我你不是用自己的信用卡
tell me you did not use one of yours.
- 我们最好打包走人 - Danny
- We better pack. - Danny.
我们刚刚赢得了一场本世纪最伟大的诈骗...
We've just pulled off the biggest con of the century...
而现在要偷偷溜出旅馆 就因为用信用卡付了账单
and we're sneaking out of a hotel for paying the bill with a bent credit card.
- 是的,骂我吧,你们为什么不骂我? - 我们骂了
- Yeah,blame me,why don't you? - We do.
我这几天过的太痛苦了,你们知道吗
I've had a very rough couple of days,you know.
全都是为了我们这个小组啊 我被推进了该死的水道里
All for the good of the team.I've been pushed in that bloody canal.
几乎快淹死了.我还触了电,差点被油炸
Nearly drowned.I been electrocuted,nearly fried.
我经历了一段非常痛苦的日子 我要让你们知道
I've had a very harrowing time,I'll have you know.
- 你有没有在听我说? - 没有
- Are you lot listening to me? - No.
- 快点,Albie - 我来了,我来了
- Come on,Albie. - I'm coming,I'm coming.